# 初几
What's the date today?
# 初三
The third (of Chinese New Year)
# 吃什么
What're we gonna eat today?
# 烙饼摊鸡蛋
Flat bread with fried eggs
# 咱们是半烫面半凉水
We make a dough by adding hot water first and then cold water.
# 咱们让这口感筋道不粘
which renders the dough more al dente and less sticky
# 倒 倒 来凉水
Go on, go on, get the cold water
# 传统做法半烫面
This is our traditional technique of making a dough
# 好
Cool
# 软硬合适 多细啊
- The texture is just right. - Look how carefully this is made!
# 鸡蛋咱们是摊鸡蛋
The eggs, we are gonna fry them
# 关键是油温合适摊这鸡蛋是两边倍儿黄
The key is to get the right oil temperature that can fry both sides golden
# 完了来点葱段酱千层烙饼
After that, stuff with some sauce and scallions in the flatbread
# 小烤鸭
Almost like Peking-duck-stuffed flatbread
# 如果全是冷水烙完不合适
It's not appropriate to use cold water to make the whole dough
# 烙完艮 硬
The texture of the flatbread would be hard and chewy
# 多刷油都不是个
And even if you add a lot of oil, you can't (soften it)
# 一半汤面一半冷水面 结合
Half warm dough and half cold dough, mixed together
# 三饼
Three pieces of flatbread
# 眼睛就是称
His eyes can weigh the dough
# 没有保密的 这饼铛必须厚点
I would not keep tip from you - the pan must be thick
# 因为传热散热比较合适
which is suitable for transferring and dissipating the heat
# 你看我也没刷油 搁在这不粘
You see I haven't used oil. It's not sticking to the board
# 看见没有特别听话
See, it's following my words
# 一头大一头小
One end be wider, and the other narrower
# 因为这头小点 我包上以后就和书皮一样
Cuz this end is narrower, after folding the dough will look like a book
# 它有层的 马上看啊
It's got layers, you'll see soon
# 咱们今天就使瓶子了啊
I'm gonna directly use the bottle
# 家里面嘛 因地制宜
It's home, so we should do according to the condition
# 大油是不层更好啊
Does lard make better layers?
# 大油口感稍为香一点
It increases the aroma a little
# 少许的盐不要多
A bit salt. Don't use too much
# 再来点薄面这点非常重要
A thin layer of flour, which is important
# 三层四层五层
Three, four, five layers
# 这时候得推着啊
Now you need to pull it a bit  #（看起来像是拉长了）
# 六 七叠
six, seven folds
# 这就为什么厨师能吹啊
This's why we say chefs are good at boasting
# 十六层非说千层饼
They don't say 16 but "thousands-of-layer" flatbread
# 稍为醒一醒啊
Let the dough rest a bit
# 小火 盖打开
Turn the fire low and open the lid
# 推着擀 不能死擀
Rolling the dough flat, you must push it gently instead of hitting and pushing hard
# 看见没有巧劲儿
Don't you see the hack?
# 要想手艺学的全 烙饼必须擀的圆
To learn in full all our skills, a perfectly round flatbread is a must
# 推着看见没有 圆了没有
See, I'm pushing it. Isn't it round?
# 这不用放油挺奇妙的
It's so intriguing that we need no oil here
# 过去我们烙饼都白扑 不许有油
In the past we were not allow to use oil when cooking flatbread
# 也不粘
It never sticked to the pan
# 就是面粉
Just flour
# 小芝麻点匀了吧 没有一点油吧
The little "sesame spots" scatter evenly on the surface, don't they? There's no oil, right?
# 老冯 打鸡蛋
Old Feng, get me the eggs!
# 激动人心的一刻到了
Here's the most exciting moment
# 这饼是没得说了 看见没这饼
You can't say too much to praise the flatbread. Don't you see it?
# 饼真漂亮
The flatbread is so pretty!
# 看看啊这是技巧
Have a look. This manifests skills
# 你为什么要敲一下老爷子讲讲
Why are you hitting the flatbread? Could you explain a little bit?
# 马上层就出来了啊
The layers' coming out
# 敲出层
And I'm hitting them out
# 老冯炒鸡蛋吧
Old Feng, I'll let you fry the eggs
# 这面是真香啊
The flatbread smells so good
# 再来点
More #（我没看出这里抓了一把什么东西？）
# 往这里打点油 来点盐
Pour some oil here, and add a bit salt
# 这个老头八十多了能做这么好的美食
This old man is more than 80 years old, and still able to make so brilliant a dish
# 这就是咱们盘道要的
That's what we are panning out here
# 油温稍为高一点啊
The oil temperature needs to be a little higher
# 完了转勺听懂了吗
And then remember the technique?
# 速度点全倒
Quickly, pour in all
# 看见没有别和弄
See? Don't mess it up
# 来吧
Come on I got this
# 这怎么吃呢
How're we gonna eat it?
# 给点酱
Get a little sauce
# 来点葱芯
A bit scallion
# 其实我们往常烙饼卷鸡蛋还有很多菜
In fact, we usually stuff the flatbread with eggs and lots of other vegetables
# 知道吧 还是奖励他
Y'know. He needs an award anyways
# 饼加鸡蛋加葱丝加酱
Flatbread with eggs, scallion shreds, and sauce
# 今天我告诉你这节可过着了
I tell you, we ARE having a festival today
# 吃着还不腻
It doesn't taste greasy either
# 给老头一个
Our old man should have one
# 美
Beautiful!
# 姑娘弄一个
We have one for our girl
# 你就争取长三斤
You should try to put on more weight
# 能体现出面香和鸡蛋香
The aroma of the flour and eggs is much highlighted
# 太香了
It smells so good
# 明天咱们吃什么
What're we gonna eat tomorrow?
# 明天咱们吃馅儿饼呗
What about stuffed flatbread? #（翻到这里发现和烙饼的翻译重合了，但是一时没想到更好的词来翻烙饼夹鸡蛋，也不能说sandwich orz）
# 初四的馅儿饼
The fourth day, stuffed flatbread day
# 锅里转
(Flatbread) Swirling in the pan!
# 明天见
See you tomorrow!
# import ending.srt 00:04:46,150